If people are um low tea, very clearly
low tea and hypothyroid
um do you start them on both at once or
uh which one do you start with?
>> In my practice it's a little different
because I'm not necessarily checking um
before we have our first visit. We're
not doing a massive lab panel. A lot of
times they'll come with pre-done labs,
but otherwise we'll focus on their
symptoms. I'm more about symptoms than
numbers. Like I'll just give you an
example. I have a normal thyroid panel
and yet I take NP thyroid and feel
better on it. Just the same way, a lot
of people can have some abnormal thyroid
parameters, doesn't always mean you need
thyroid, especially when you start them
on testosterone first. And a lot of
times they'll get their lifestyles in
order a little better when they're
taking the testosterone and they feel
great. And then I'm like, well then I'm
not going to go just off of a thyroid
panel per se when you feel well. So for
me and the way it sort of happens in my
practice in general, we're not exploring
the thyroid part at the same time. Um if
they already come to me from another
clinic and they've been on let's say
thyroid like levothyroxine, cynthroidid,
something like that, we will discuss
switching over to a desiccated thyroid,
I still try to do testosterone first.
Leave them on the levo for at least
three to four weeks while they're
getting adjusted to the testosterone.
Then we still address the the thyroid
conversion after the fact. That's not
all of them, not a 100% of cases. I
think there have been some like, "No, I
want to go ahead and switch to NP. I'm
ready to, you know, they've hated Levo
for as long as they've been on it." And
that's fine. I just tell them, we we're
messing with two variables at a time.
So, you just got to be open to knowing
we may not know what's doing what.